Printed Maps Printed.Maps
American Philosophical Society
- North America
  - United States Of America
    - Pennsylvania
      - Railroad map of Pennsylvania. Published by the Department of Internal Affairs of Pennsylvania. Drawn and compiled by J. Sutton Wall. N.p.: 1910., 967; Scale: 1 in. = 6 mi.; Size: 86.8 x 141.4 cm.; Colored.; J. Sutton Wall.
        Presented by Francis S. Mcllhenny.
      - Map of New Sweden; 1638-1655. Philadelphia: S.J. Clarke Pub. Co.: [1912]., 968; Size: 16.3 x 9.6 cm.; Gregory S. Keen.
        In: Ellis Paxson Oberholtzer, Philadelphia, a history of the city and its people. Philadelphia: S. J. Clarke Pub. Co.: [1912]. 4 vols. See vol. 1, facing p. 12.
      - Map of the location [of] Union and Confederate corps and division hospitals on Gettysburg battlefield, July 1863. U.S. Gettysburg National Park Commission. N.p.: 1915., 969; Scale: 1 in. = 2,000 ft.; Size: 46.2 x 47.7 cm.; John P. Nicholson, E. B. Cope, and E. M. Hewitt.
        Blueprint.
      - Map of the battlefield of Gettysburg from original surveys by the engineers of the commission. By the authority of the Hon. Newton D. Baker, Secretary of War, July 1st. 1916, under the direction of the Gettysburg National Park Commission. U.S. Army. Corps of Engineers. Philadelphia: John T. Palmer Company: 1916., 970; Scale: 6 in. = 4200 ft.; Size: 117 x 84.6 cm.; Colored.; S. A. Hammond.
      - Perspective view of Gettysburg National Military Park. U.S. Gettysburg National Park Commission. [Washington: 1916-1919]., 971; Size: 43 x 53.5 cm.; Colored.; John P. Nicholson and E. B. Cope.
      - Pennsylvania showing counties in different colors - townships - cities - boroughs - villages -postoffices - steam and electric railways, with stations and distances between stations and other features - complete index to all places on map showing location and population according to latest official census. Published by National Map Co. Indianapolis, Ind.: National Map Co.: [ca. 1922]., 972; Scale: 1 in. = 5¼ mi.; Size: 91.5 x 149 cm.; Colored.
        Inset:Congressional and state senatorial districts.
      - Composite map showing the Mason-Dixon Line, compiled by Thomas D. Cope from U.S. Geological Survey maps: Pennsylvania-Delaware-Coatesville quadrangle; Pennsylvania-Delaware-West Chester quadrangle; Pennsylvania-Delaware-New Jersey quadrangle; Pennsylvania-New Jersey-Philadelphia quadrangle; Pennsylvania-McCalls Ferry quadrangle; Pennsylvania-Quarryville quadrangle. [Washington]: 1924-1926., 973; 8 pieces.; Size: 215.3 x 44.3 cm.; Colored.
        See: Thomas D. Cope, Collection of reprints on Mason and Dixon (974.5:C79).
        Shows lines run by [William?] Talbot in 1683, Benjamin Chambers in 1688, and John Taylor in 1732-33.
        Contains also: Blueprint of the states of Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Delaware, Maryland and West Virginia (22.5 x 29.5 cm.). Title: Mason and Dixon's Line established by agreement made in 1732. Located & milestones put in from 1763 to 1767...
        Also: Photostat of original drawing of map showing the area between the Delaware and the Susquehanna Rivers. 44 x 26 cm.
        Presented by Thomas D. Cope.
      - Map of Penn's manors superimposed on a modern map by Fred G. Gorman, January 9, 1937. Highway map of southeastern Pennsylvania. Compiled from records of Pennsylvania Department of Highways, the Montgomery County Commissioners, the U.S. Geological Survey. [Philadelphia: 1937]., 974; Scale: 1 in. = 2 mi.; Size: 40.5 x 49.6 cm.; Fred J. Gorman.
        Presented by Arthur Bloch, 3 December 1952.
      - A map of some of the south and east bounds of Pennsylvania in America being partially inhabited [by William Penn?]. London: John Thornton and John Seller: [1681]. Meriden Gravure Co.: 1943., 975; Scale: 1 in. = 6 mi.; Size: 41.7 x 51.1 cm.; Colored.; William Penn.
        Facsimile reproduced in collotype by the Meriden Gravure Company from the original in the John Carter Brown Library: 1943.
        With "a description at the end of it; and some proposals." Accompanied by "A note on the William Penn map of Pennsylvania" [London: 1681].
      - Plans of Benjamin Chambers' and John Taylor's boundary line of southern Pennsylvania. 1688., [1949?].; 976; Scale: 1 in. = 200 ft.; Size of paper: ca. 39 x 448.3 cm.; Colored.; Benjamin Chambers, John Taylor, and Fred J. Gorman.
        Photograph, ca. 1949.
        Presented by Fred J. Gorman, 30 June 1949.
      - Birdsboro quadrangle. Pennsylvania. Berks County. U.S. Geological Survey. [Washington]: 1950., 977; Scale: 1:24,000.; Size: 57.9 x 44.4 cm.; Colored.
      - Oil and gas fields of Pennsylvania. Geological Survey of Pennsylvania. Fourth series. Compiled by Thomas H. Jones and Lillian Heeren. N.p.: 1953., 978; Scale: 1 in. = 6 mi.; Size: 69 x 118.2 cm.; Colored.; Thomas H. Jones and Lillian Heeren.
        Pipelines shown on reverse side of this map.
      - Media quadrangle. Pennsylvania. U.S. Geological Survey. [Washington]: 1955., 979; Scale: 1:24,000.; Size: 57.7 x 44.5 cm.; Colored.
      - Lansdowne quadrangle. Pennsylvania. U.S. Geological Survey. [Washington]: 1956., 980; Scale: 1:24,000.; Size: 57.7 x 44.5 cm.; Colored.
      - A map for the Welcome Society of Pennsylvania, shewing the most travelled roads from sundry places to W[illia]m Penn's manor of Pennsbury. Ao. Di. 1935. [Philadelphia]: 1956., 981; Size: 16.5 x 24.8 cm.; Wm. M. Campbell.
        Inset: From Holme's map begun in 1681 shewing some of the proprietary's manors, including Pennsbury.
        Presented by William Jacob Robbins, November 1956.
      - Boyertown quadrangle. Pennsylvania. U.S. Geological Survey. [Washington]: 1957., 982; Scale: 1:24,000.; Size: 57.8 x 44.4 cm.; Colored.
      - Combination atlas map of Montgomery County, Pennsylvania. Compiled, drawn & published from personal examinations and surveys: J. D. Scott. Philadelphia: Thos. Hunter: 1877. Reprinted in 1959. 41 pages of maps, cover, title page, introduction, and index., 983; Size of paper: 28 x 21.5 cm.; Colored.; J. D. Scott.
        Presented by the Montgomery County Planning Commission, October 1959. Re-issued in honor of the 175th anniversary of Montgomery County, September 1959. Contains list of townships and boroughs.
      - Geologic map of Pennsylvania. Topographic and Geologic Survey of Pennsylvania. Fourth series. Carlisle Gray, state geologist. Washington: Williams & Heintz Map Corporation: 1960., 984; Scale: 1:250,000.; Size: 144.7 x 203.4 cm.; Colored.; Carlyle Gray, R. R. Conlin, D. M. Hoskins, M. N. Shaffner, A. A. Sokolow, D. B. McLaughlin, A. R. Geyer, A. S. Gate, V. C. Shepps, W. S. Lytle, J. M. Bergsten, J. T. Miller, G. H. Wood, Jr., H. H. Arndt, T. M, Kehn, and A. E. van Olden.
      - Subsurface structure of plateau region of north-central and western Pennsylvania on top of Oriskany formation. Geological Survey of Pennsylvania. Fourth series. N.p.: 1961., 985; Scale: 14 cm. = 25 mi.; Size: 103.8 x 129.8 cm.; Addison S. Cate and C. R. Fettke.
        See: Geological Survey of Pennsylvania, Bulletin. 1953, pl. 3.
      - Plan of Keim's addition to Port Clinton. Philadelphia: Childs: [n.d.], 986; Scale: 1 in. = 200 ft.; Size: 33.3 x 49.6 cm.; Childs.
        Endorsement: "Ask W. J. Duane for a map drawn by Christian Brobst." See map 649: [ca. 1835]: B81msc.
        On reverse: manuscript map in pencil of central Pennsylvania showing Danville & Catawissa, etc.
      - Philadelphia
        - Portraiture of the city of Philadelphia in the province of Pennsylvania in America. By Thomas Holme, surveyor. London: Andrew Sowle: [1683]., 987; Scale: ca. ¾ in. = 528 ft.; Size: 30 x 45 cm.; Thomas Holme.
          Inset: Peninsula between Delaware and Schuylkill Rivers.
          Presented by General Parker from the library of Zaccheus Collins, 1831.
        - A plan of the city of Philadelphia; the Battery; & the State House. Also, a small copy of "An East Prospect of the city.. ." Engraved and published by T. Jefferys. London: [1756]., 988; Size: 50 x 93.5 cm.; Nicholas Scull.; Thomas Jefferys.
        - [Map of Philadelphia. 1774]., 989; Size: 49.5 x 49.8 cm.
          In: John Reed, An explanation of the map of the city and liberties of Philadelphia. Philadelphia: 1774.
          Presented by John Reed, March 1816.
        - .. .Map of the city and liberties of Philadelphia, with the catalogue of purchasers, is humbly dedicated by their most obedient humble servant, John Reed. [Philadelphia]: T. Man: [1774]., 990; Scale: 1 in. = 100 perches.; Size: 75.4 x 150.5 cm.; James Smither.; John Reed.
          Inset: Philadelphia; vignettes of the State House, Pennsylvania Hospital, and the house of employment and the alms house.
          See: John Reed, An explanation of the city and liberties of Philadelphia. Philadelphia: 1774.
          Wheat: 457
        - [Map of the western part of Philadelphia. 1774]., 991; Size: 33.5 x 16 cm.
          In: John Reed, An explanation of the city and liberties of Philadelphia. Philadelphia: 1774.
        - To the Honourable House of Representatives of the freemen of Pennsylvania this map of the city and liberties of Philadelphia with the catalogue of purchasers is humbly dedicated by their most obedient humble servant Iohn Reed. [1774]., 992; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 100 perches.; Size: 75.5 x 49.7 cm.; James Smither.; John Reed?
          In: John Reed, An explanation of the map of the city. [1774].
          Presented by Joseph Reed, 15 March 1816.
        - Map of Philadelphia and parts adjacent. By N. Scull and G. Heap. N.p.: [1777]., 993; Scale: 1 in. = 8 furlongs.; Size: 33.9 x 29.5 cm.; N. Scull and G. Heap.
          See: Gentleman's Magazine, 1777, vol. 47, opp. p. 573, for American edition of map.
          Wheat: 455
        - Philadelphie, par Eas[t]burn. Paris: Le Rouge: [ca. 1777]., 994; Scale: 1 in. = 900 English ft.; Size: 21.2 x 35.1 cm.; Colored.; B. Eastburn.
        - Seat of war in the environs of Philadelphia. By Thomas Kitchin. [London]: R. Baldwin: [1777]., 995; Size: 19.2 x 25 cm.; Thomas Kitchin.
          At top of map is: "For the London Magazine, 1777."
        - A plan of the city and environs of Philadelphia, with the works and encampments of His Majesty's forces. Under the command of Lieutenant General Sir William Howe, K.B. London: Wm. Faden: 1779 [1 January 1779]., 996; Scale: 3 in. = 1 mi.; Size: 51.7 x 47.3 cm.; William Faden.
          Reproduction by Historic Urban Plans: Ithaca, New York: 1965.
          Presented by Dr. John W. Reps.
        - [Plan of thirty-six lots between Locust and Spruce Streets on Twelfth, in Philadelphia. 1792]., 997; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 85 ft.; Size: 11.8 x 6 cm.
          In: Dunlap's American Daily Advertiser. 10 March 1792.
          Wheat: 460
        - Map of Philadelphia. From "Plan of the City of Philadelphia and environs." [Philadelphia]: 1796., 998; Size: 16 x 21.4 cm.; John Hills.
          Photograph from original in the Library of Congress.
          Wheat: 468
          See: Philip Lee Phillips, A descriptive list of maps and views of Philadelphia. [Philadelphia: 1926].
        - Plan of the city of Philadelphia. [1796]., 999; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 90 perches.; Size: 24.3 x 36 cm.
          In: Thomas Stephens, Stephens' Philadelphia directory, for 1796, frontispiece.
          Wheat: 467
        - Plan of the city of Philadelphia. [1797]., 1000; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 90 perches.; Size: 24.3 x 36 cm.; J. Bowes.
          In: Cornelius W. Stafford, The Philadelphia Directory for 1797, frontispiece.
          Wheat: 470
        - To the citizens of Philadelphia, this plan of the city and its environs is respectfully dedicated by the editor. [Philadelphia: 1802]., [ca. 1802].; 1001; Scale: 1 in. = 75 perches.; Size of paper: 45.8 x 61 cm.; Colored.; P. C. Varle.; Scott.
          Insets: City Hall, State House, and Congress Hall; Library Company of Philadelphia library; First United States Bank.
        - Plan of the city of Philadelphia. London: James Cundee: 1807 [7 March 1870]., 1002; Scale: 1 in. = 100 perches.; Size: 15.9 x 24.8 cm.
          See: Charles William Janson, The stranger in America. London: J. Cundee: 1807, p. 175.
        - Plan of the city of Philadelphia and environs. Surveyed by John Hills in the summers of 1801, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, & 7. Philadelphia: John Hills: 1808., 1003; Scale: Distance between the circles is one mile.; Size: 100.6 x 100.6 cm. In 10 circles, outermost circle 99 cm. diameter.; John Hills.; William Kneass.
          Contains engravings of the Philadelphia Water Works and Cape Henlopen lighthouse.
        - To the citizens of Philadelphia, this new plan of the city and its environs. Taken from actual survey.. .[and] drawn under the direction of J. A. Paxton by William Strickland. [Philadelphia]: C. P. Harrison: 1811 [1 January 1811]., 1004; Scale: 1 in. = 1,000 ft.; Size: 45.8 x 49.7 cm.; Colored.; W. Harrison.; William Strickland.
          To accompany: Paxton's stranger's guide.
        - This new map of the city of Philadelphia for the use of fire men and others is most respectfully dedicated to the citizens and members of the engine & hose companies, by... John A. Paxton. [Philadelphia: ca. 1816]., 1005; Size: 35.4 x 61.2 cm.; Size of paper: 47.5 x 61.2 cm.; W. Strickland.
          Contains: a listing of engine & hose houses; a vignette of the Fair Mount Water Works; an extension of the northwestern end of the map of the city to include Fair Mount; and cut away diagrams of two fire plugs.
        - Map of Philadelphia County, constructed by virtue of an act of the legislature of Pennsylvania. By John Melish. 1816. Philadelphia: Melish: 1819 [14 April 1819]., 1006; Scale: 1 in. = 1¼ mi.; Size: 43.4 x 49 cm.; Colored.; J. Melish.; Tanner, Vallance, Kearny, & Company.
        - To the hose companies of Philadelphia this plan of the city is inscribed. The first hose company instituted in 1803. Philadelphia: W. Kneass: [ca. 1820]., 1007; Size: 37.9 x 38.7 cm.; Colored.; W. Kneass.; William Strickland.
          Inset: Engraving of Center Square water works.
        - Plan of the city of Philadelphia, compiled from actual surveys by F. Drayton, 1824. Philadelphia: 1824., 1008; Scale: 1 in. = 2,000 ft.; Size: 28.7 x 23.9 cm.; Colored.; F. Drayton.; R. M. Filbert.
        - Philadelphia & environs. Philadelphia: H. S. Tanner: [1825]., 1009; Scale: 1 in. = 2 mi.; Size: 17.2 x 10.5 cm.
          Autograph inscription: George Merrick from H. S. Tanner, esqr., Phila.
          Published in A general outline of the United States. Philadelphia: H.S. Tanner: 1825, p. 122.
          Presented by Henry S. Tanner, July 1825.
        - A map of Philadelphia and adjacent country. Philadelphia: H. S. Tanner: [ca. 1826]., 1010; Scale: 1 in. = 2 mi.; Size: 28 x 37.2 cm.; Colored.
          Presented by H. S. Tanner, 5 March 1830.
        - Philadelphia. [London]: Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge: 1840., 1011; Scale: 2 in. = 3,000 ft.; Size: 28.8 x 37.5 cm.; Colored.
          Contains vignettes of the Second U.S. Bank and the Merchants' Exchange.
        - Map of Washington Square, Walnut Street, Philadelphia. [Philadelphia]: M. Schmitz & P. Kereven: 1843., 1012; Scale: 1 in. = 30 ft.; Size: 47 x 47 cm.; Size of paper: 63.4 x 85.6 cm.; John B. Colahan and M. Schmitz.; T. Sinclair.
          The botanical and English names of the trees on this map were collected with great care, and their position given by Patrick Kereven, chief gardener of Wash[i]ng[ton] & Indepen[den]ce Squares.
          Presented by Thomas Sinclair, 26 May 1843.
        - A plan of the city and environs of Philadelphia. Surveyed by N. Scull and G. Heap. London: W. Faden: 1777. Philadelphia: Thomas Fisher: 1847., 1013; Scale: 1:47,520; Size: 62.7 x 45.4 cm.; Colored.; N. Scull and G. Heap.; W. Faden.
          Copy of Faden's map originally in W. Faden, The North American Atlas. Republished by Thomas Fisher, 1847.
          Contains vignette of the State House.
          Presented by Thomas Fisher, 19 February 1847.
        - Map of the city of Philadelphia, together with all the surrounding districts, including Camden, N. J., from official records, plans of the district surveyor & original surveys by J. C. Sydney. 1849. Philadelphia: Smith & Wistar: 1849., 1014; Scale: 1 in. = 450 ft.; Size: 171 x 173.5 cm.; Colored.; J. C. Sydney.; P. S. Duval.
          Presented 12 July 1849.
        - Philadelphia. Published by A. McElroy, Philadelphia 1849. Philadelphia: A. McElroy and P. S. Duval: 1849., 1015; Scale: 1 in. = 1,000 ft.; Size: 43 x 35.3 cm.; N. Friend.
        - An east prospect of the city of Philadelphia, taken by George Heap from the Jersey shore, under the direction of Nicholas Scull. 1754. Philadelphia: E. H. Coggins: 1854., 1016; Scale: 4 furloughs or ½ a mile.; Size: 20 x 45.6 cm.; Size of paper: 60.5 x 96.1 cm.; George Heap and Nicholas Scull.; Gerard Vandergucht.; L. N. Rosenthal.
          Insets: The battery, and the State House.
          John Vaughan presented "An East Prospect.. ." 1752, 2 November 1810.
        - An outline of the newly consolidated city [of Philadelphia] showing the boundaries of the wards, according to the act, passed by the Legislature, Jany. 31st, 1854. Philadelphia: R. L. Barnes: 1854., 1017; size: 64.5 x 50.4 cm.; Colored.; Friend & Aub.
        - Philadelphia. No. 21. New York: J. H. Colton & Co.:, 1855.; 1018; Scale: 1 in. = 650 yd.; Size: 40.5 x 31.6 cm.; Colored.; George W. Colton.
          See: George W. Colton, Colton's atlas of the world, illustrating physical and political geography. New York: J. H. Colton & Co.: 1856.
        - Scott's map of the consolidated city of Philadelphia, from the latest records and actual surveys. Philadelphia: Scott & Moore: 1855., 1019; Size: 164.5 x 189.5 cm.; Colored.; E. Herrlein.
          Inset: Map of Philadelphia County. Also contains business directory of the subscribers to the map, engravings of the Independence Hall complex, Merchants' Exchange, Laurel Hill cemetery, and Girard College.
          Purchased "for the use of the Society" in 1855.
        - Philadelphia water front. Delaware River, Pennsylvania. U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey. [Washington]: 1891., 1020; Scale: 1:9600.; Size: 129.4 x 66 cm.; F. R. Hassler, C. M. Eakin, S. C. McCorkle, F. W. Perkins, W. M. Boyce, R. M. Bache, J. Hergesheimer, H. L. Marindin, E. O. Kendall, J. E. Hilgard,J. Lock, C. A. Schott, E. Goodfellow, J. B. Baylor, E. Smith, and C. M. Thomas.
        - Philadelphia water front. U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey. Schuylkill River, Pennsylvania. [Washington]: 1891., 1021; Scale: 1:9,600.; Size: 129.2 x 65.9 cm.; F. R. Hassler, C. M. Eakin, R. M. Bache, S. C. McCorkle, W. M. Boyce, P. J. Hergesheimer, H. L. Marindin, E. O. Kendall, John Locke, C. A. Schott, E. Goodfellow, J. B. Baylor, J. E. Hilgard, E. Smith, and C. M. Thomas.
        - Plan showing improvements in the 21st, 22nd, and 34th wards, and Fairmount Park, north of Girard Avenue, Philadelphia, 1893. Philadelphia: Century Lith. Co.: 1893., 1022; Size: 63.4 x 113.5 cm.; Century Lithograph Company.; Chester E. Albright.
          Insets: View of proposed Falls bridge over Schuylkill river; Memorial Hall; Country Club House, Gentlemen's driving park; Wissahickon Inn; Park Boulevard from City Hall; Manheim; Midvale Avenue, under P.& R.R.R.
          Presented by Margah Toogood Flood, September 1958.
        - New map of the city of Philadelphia from the latest city surveys. Prepared for Gopsill's directories. Philadelphia: J. L. Smith: 1896., 1023; Scale: 3 in. = 1 mi.; Size: ca. 101 x 72 cm.; Colored.
        - Philadelphia and vicinity. Pennsylvania and New Jersey. U.S. Geological Survey. Charles D. Walcott, director. [Washington]: 1894. Edition of June 1896., 1024; Scale: 1:62,500.; Size: 91.5 x 71.3 cm.; Colored.; Henry Gannett, C. D. Walcott, H. M. Wilson, Frank Sutton, J. H. Jennings, R. D. Cummin, W. H. Lovell, E. B. Clark, and Robert Muldrow.
        - New map of the city of Philadelphia from the latest city surveys. Prepared for Gopsill's directories. Philadelphia: J. L. Smith: 1901., 1025; Scale: 3 in. = 1 mi.; Size: ca. 101 x 72 cm.; Colored.
        - Philadelphia and vicinity. Pennsylvania and New Jersey. U.S. Geological Survey. Charles D. Walcott, director. [Washington]: 1902. Edition of February 1902., 1026; Scale: 1:62,500.; Size: 91.5 x 71.3 cm.; Colored.; Henry Gannett, C. D. Walcott, H. M. Wilson, Frank Sutton, J. H. Jennings, R. D. Cummin, W. H. Lovell, E. B. Clark, and Robert Muldrow.
        - New map of the city of Philadelphia from the latest city surveys. Prepared for Gopsill's directories. Philadelphia: J. L. Smith: 1906., 1027; Scale: 3 in. = 1 mi.; Size: ca. 101 x 72 cm.; Colored.
        - The Philadelphia Parkway as planned for the Fairmount Park Association. Horace Trumbauer, C. C. Zantzinger, and Paul P. Cret. [Philadelphia: 1908]., 1028; Size: 66.7 x 66.7 cm.; Horace Trumbauer, C. C. Zantzinger, and Paul P. Cret.
          See: Philadelphia Fairmount Park Art Association, Report of the Commission.... Philadelphia: 1908.
        - Map of Philadelphia, Camden and vicinity. Compiled from city plans and personal surveys. Philadelphia: C. E. Howe Company: 1910., 1029; Scale: 1 in. = 2,000 ft.; Size: 133.2 x 104.2 cm.; Colored.; Elvino V. Smith.
        - New map of Philadelphia and vicinity. Philadelphia: J. L. Smith: 1913-1914., 1030; Scale: 1 in. = 1 mi.; Size: 167.2 x 110.8 cm.
          Contains autograph of Francis J. Packard.
        - Philadelphia, by the City Planning Division, Bureau of Engineer & Surveys. No. 9. 1 January 1928., 1031; Size: 41 x 124 cm.
        - General plan of Girard College, Philadelphia, Pa., 1932., 1032; Size: 29.7 x 106.5 cm.; Day & Zimmermann.
          Photograph in two pieces of architects' plan, 24 April 1930, and revised 20 January 1932.
          Presented by Girard College, May 1967.
        - A map of old Philadelphia on which are indicated buildings of architectural interest that were built during the 18th. and early 19th. centuries and are still standing Ao. Di. 1932, two hundred and fifty years after the founding of the city by William Penn. Philadelphia: J. L. Smith Co.: 1934., 1033; Size: 52.2 x 77.1 cm.; Colored.; William M. Campbell.
          Inset: Philadelphia from the map made by John Reed in 1774; also contains pictures of Independence Hall, William Penn, B. Franklin, Stephen Girard, and William Penn and the Indians.
          Made by a committee of the Philadelphia chapter of the American Institute of Architecture.
        - Roads and bridle paths, Wissahickon Valley, Fairmount Park, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Friends of the Wissahickon, Inc. Philadelphia: 1940., 1034; Scale: 1 in. = 1,000 ft.; Size: 83.5 x 47.7 cm.; Colored.; Ralph Weston Jones.
          Presented by the Friends of the Wissahickon, Inc., February 1940.
        - Map of the Schuylkill River from Fairmount to the Falls, showing the roads and residences which existed in the adjacent territory before 1850. Prepared and rendered for the Modern Club, 1941. By Henry B. McIntire. 1941. N.p.: 1941., 1035; Size: 24.8 x 47.2 cm.; Size of photograph: 27 x 73.7 cm.; Henry B. Mclntire.
          Two panels in memoriam: Warwick James Price.
        - Preliminary plans for Old City Area, by the Philadelphia City Planning Commission. [Philadelphia]: 1947., 1036; Size: 40.6 x 51.2 cm.
          Includes the present Independence National Historic Park.
        - A map of Philadelphia; published November 1, 1762 by Matthew Clarkson and Mary Biddle. Republished November, 1858, by Joseph H. Bonsall and Samuel L. Smedley from whose lithograph, in the possession of the Library Company of Philadelphia, this facsimile is reproduced in March, 1957, by the Society of Colonial Wars in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. N.p.: 1957., 1037; Scale: 1 in. = 400 ft.; Size: 49 x 65.7 cm.; Matthew Clarkson and Mary Biddle.
          Presented by Thomas D. Cope, 23 May 1957.